<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Randomness of Robcamstone]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Randomness of Robcamstone]]></description><link>https://Robcamstone.github.io</link><image><url>https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8862/18327411741_b5d085589b_o_d.jpg</url><title>The Randomness of Robcamstone</title><link>https://Robcamstone.github.io</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 13:53:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Robcamstone.github.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[TV in my life time]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<div class="title">Opportunity knocks</div>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="#_freddie_davies">Freddie Davies</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="#_bonnie_langford">Bonnie Langford</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="#_lena_zavaroni">Lena Zavaroni</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_freddie_davies">Freddie Davies</h3>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dYVYEFRe58s?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_bonnie_langford">Bonnie Langford</h3>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/noRliAEeiQE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_lena_zavaroni">Lena Zavaroni</h3>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j9NSwN-adPM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1630-TV-in-my-life-time.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1630-TV-in-my-life-time.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Campbell Stonebanks]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Secondary School]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Catford Boys had classes Named "A" though to "H" with "H" being the class with the pupils they had written of from day one and so made no attempt to educate, which is why when I left school in 1977 at sixteen I could still not read or write.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I enjoyed technical drawing and art at school, but only when I was in the mood.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><span class="image"><a class="image" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robcamstone/sets/72157651606594698/"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7645/17177655245_f948fff392_q_d.jpg" alt="image" width="135"></a></span>
<span class="image"><a class="image" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robcamstone/sets/72157651606594698/"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7607/17177063261_034605e732_q_d.jpg" alt="image" width="135"></a></span>
<span class="image"><a class="image" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robcamstone/sets/72157651606594698/"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7659/16991469729_bfd823fa13_q_d.jpg" alt="image" width="135"></a></span>
<span class="image"><a class="image" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robcamstone/sets/72157651606594698/"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7590/16557491783_b6341bbe98_q_d.jpg" alt="image" width="135"></a></span>
<span class="image"><a class="image" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robcamstone/sets/72157651606594698/"><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8726/17176029712_25097d5952_q_d.jpg" alt="image" width="135"></a></span>
<span class="image"><a class="image" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robcamstone/sets/72157651606594698/"><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8749/16557499983_b6ab9143fe_q_d.jpg" alt="image" width="135"></a></span></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Many a time I would just sit in the art class just staring of into space. Enjoying the world in my mind as I had no need for the so called real world (External world).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I spent a lot of time crying at school as I was forced to interact with a world I had no interest in.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the early days of being in secondary school I enjoyed the music and history lessons but that change when the teachers teaching us change.
The music teacher had this trick of if he got call away from the classroom he would leave his glasses on his desk and when he came back he would put them back on and scan the class and then point out any pupil(s) that had left their desk or misbehaved in some other way of cause he must have been peeping though the window but it worked as he always got the right pupil(s) and after a couple of times no pupil would misbehave while he was out of the classroom.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The history teacher we first had was way ahead of his time in that he use cartoons and speech bubbles on the blackboard to help him teach us.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We first learnt about boats and this lead on to the discover of other countries and peoples which then lead on to other things. It was a great way to teach starting out with something invented by man and then showing how its creation effected history. I thing after the boat he went back in time to the wheel and we followed the effect it had on history. After 2 year we got a different history teacher I don&#8217;t how much he knew about history but sure didn&#8217;t know how to teach it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>He was the head teacher of the 4th year and was more interested in fulfilling his life ambition of caning ever pupil in the school and everyday after assembly he would have a long list of pupils to call out to go to his office to receive the cane.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When my turn came I asked him why I was receiving the cane as how would I know what I should not do again unless I knew the reason why. He was unable to give a reason and I asked how can he cane a pupil if he doesn&#8217;t know what for and that he must have a reason as he had got to put into a book the reason why a pupil was to be caned. He backed down in the end but said if I told anybody then he would cane me.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>He was not the only teacher who was into abusing pupils the fencing master use to punish a pupil by striking them across the stomach with his sabre. I only discovered that fact after I join his fencing class.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A few years after I left the school I heard he final got the sack after he cut a pupil, but he should have got more then just the sack he should have been changed with physical abuse of a minor.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_sports_day">Sports Day</h3>
<div class="imageblock" style="float: right">
<div class="content">
<a class="image" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fencing_foil_valid_surfaces_2009.svg"><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/14/Fencing_foil_valid_surfaces_2009.svg/263px-Fencing_foil_valid_surfaces_2009.svg.png" alt="Target area for foil" width="150"></a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fridays was sports day and every pupil had to do a sport of some sort.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I chose fencing and was quite good at it, but without asking me I was put in to fence for the school which I was very upset about, but my mum made me go and came to watch. So one of my Saturdays was wasted going to school to fence.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The first round was done in the main hall and so I had to put on a good show, but I felt I had done enough to not go though to the next round and so went and got changed, so was very upset when over the PA came the list of fencers that had gone though to the next round and my name was among them.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thankfully the second round I fenced in was done in a classroom and so I was able to insure I never got though.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the Monday I asked to change from fencing to swimming.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I first switched to swimming I did go, but soon got bored with it, I&#8217;ve never enjoyed swimming in a pool but I do enjoy swimming in the sea.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So I soon stopped taking my swimming things and so got to sit in a classroom with the other pupils that had not brought their sports stuff and so could do their home work, but as I never had home work because of being in class &quot;H&quot; I could spend the time in my own world. So Fridays during the sports hour was the best times I had at school.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1620-Secondary-School.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1620-Secondary-School.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Campbell Stonebanks]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Family holidays]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Family holidays were spent at Wallasey, Merseyside where we stayed with my mum&#8217;s Sister and her (sister&#8217;s) second husband in Trafalgar Road.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I would think we were the only faimly to use the coastline of the River Mersey as a beach and even paddled and swam in it despite the patches of oil on the beach at the time we were there (1970s).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My Brothers, sisters and cousins use to go swimming at the Guinea Gap Baths, I can only recall going once to swim, but may have gone more times but I prefer to swim in the sea or a river then at the swimming baths, so I tended to go and so called watch my family swim (it gave me time to be in my own world).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I hated the journey from Catford to Wallasey and would role myself up into the fetal position for large parts of the journey. To this day I don&#8217;t like going on trips (A feeling of great sadness comes over me). I think it&#8217;s due to my ASD and/or social anxiety disorder and leaving the know for the unknown, but must be more to it as the feeling is sadness and not fear. Coming back home which should have made me happy was hard and I would not only role up into a ball but cry as well, but that was because I was leaving behind the only person I have ever truly cared about and sadly we would break each others hearts over the years (April 13, 1994 was to be the last day we would spend together and now I only see her in my dreams).</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1610-Family-holidays.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1610-Family-holidays.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Campbell Stonebanks]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 16:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Under 5 Years Old]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I use to enjoy singing and taking of Freddie Davies, but being so young have no memory of seeing him for the first time on Opportunity Knocks.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I enjoyed the laugher of my family including various uncles and aunts but when I got to around 5 or 6 years old I stopped talking and lost interest in interacting with others and the world around me. I could talk I just chose not to (selective mutism).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I disliked primary school and cried a lot, so much so that my father for the first year, was always being called in by the school to take me home (He was a Foreman Baker and so worked nights).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The only thing I learn by the time I left Plassy Road School, Rushey Green, Catford was that if you are different for any reason that&#8217;s reason enough for others to judge and bully you. The year I left was the school&#8217;s last year it closed at the end of that years' term.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_saturday_morning_pictures">Saturday Morning Pictures</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<a class="image" href="http://cinematreasures.org/theaters/28141/photos/87590"><img src="http://photos.cinematreasures.org/production/photos/87590/1384617465/large.jpg" alt="large.jpg"></a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>During the late 60s and the 70s must Saturday&#8217;s were spent at Saturday Morning Pictures at the ABC Cinema in Catford.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1600-Under-5-Years-Old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://Robcamstone.github.io/2017/02/06/1600-Under-5-Years-Old.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Campbell Stonebanks]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>